KHALYANN CHAKRAVERTHY

Marketing & Branding Expert I Brand Growth Strategist I Digital Marketer

AREASOFEXPERTISE

Marketing Communication Brand Management GTM strategy Digital Marketing Operations

FUNCTIONALSKILLS

Leadership Interpersonal skills Team Handling Communication Negotiation Collaborative

EDUCATION

Master of Business Administration Madras University 1998 - 2000

CERTIFICATION

Facebook Blueprint
Advanced Certification in DM
& Communication from MICA

PROFILE

Marketing Manager and Branding Expert with 20 years of experience. Having a unique blend of creative vision and business sense, I am dynamic and multi lingual Branding Expert known for my astute understanding of various Digital Marketing and Traditional Marketing, and offline Media Activities. A keen marketer who loves the rewarding challenge of building a brand online and offline.

EXPERIENCE

Mecwin Technologies India Pvt Ltd - Head Branding and Marketing - (March 2022 - till date

- Leveraging the social handles for the company to build online presence that generates business and educates the audience on sustainable energy resources that we deal in.
- Gathering and evaluating client's feedback to brush up on the services and products that we offer
- Understanding the current of the market demand to align branding of the company outlets
- Authoritative for in shop branding and digital marketing strategies including website and content updates.
- Handling the PR aspects by building sustainable relationships with key media personnel in India

RP SOLAR

Marketing Specialist with RP Solar - (July 2020 - March 2022)

- Responsible for building marketing strategies to reach target audience, offer them engagement opportunities
- Skillfully evaluating marketing budgets, allocating spending on various marketing needs accordingly and optimizing money to full fill the needs for the renewable energy
- Performing site audits to evaluate the most impactful installation of Solar panels to harness the power of sun in an efficient manner.
- Successfully managed the marketing strategies by maintaining the Social media presence, and identifying new opportunities to encourage customer engagement while overseeing the accounts towards ROI goals and being up to date with market trends and seasonality.

LUMINOUS

Regional Marketing Manager - (July 2013 - February 2019)

- Managed offline branding by putting various events, schemes, roadshows, campaigns, social media activities, online and offline media activities execution while handling 4 states and subsequent regional teams.
- Spearheaded the Magical 25 scheme in TN, which increased product sales 100% while handling high-end events at the tune of a 2.5 Cr budget driving growth of 10%
- Was instrumental in creating varied marketing plans & strategies in order to improve product visibility and positively affect the company's overall growth.
- Interacted with various managerial heads & teams to understand their vision for marketing, sales and overall development. Made sure that marketing plans were in tune with the vision & took corrective measures as required from time to time.
- Handed various teams. Communicated with them, trained & mentored them as required

CMO AXIS

Marketing Program – Manager (Dec'11 – Mar'13)

- Handled the entire marketing cycle i.e., from strategy planning to execution including quantifiable results, for various clients.
- Facilitated marketing activities for various industry-based clients like Vasan Eye Care, HindustanUniversity, CII, Bean etc.
- Coordinated with the client management teams to understand their expectations with regards to approach and result. Accordingly, created plans, reviewed the same and finalized them after detailed deliberations and discussions with relevant authorities.

ACHIEVEMENTS &AWARDS

- Best Employee of the year BWW (2003)
- Best Team Player Regional Operations BWW (2004)
- CMO Super Star
 CMO Axis (2012)
- Way To Go
 Luminous Power
 Technologies Ltd. (2017)

CONTACTINFO

Ph no. 7397292333 Email Id:- khalyann@gmail.com Location : Bengaluru

- Handled a team of sales & marketing executives, tele sales and others in order to make sure that the marketing activities were executed with result oriented focus.
- Provided continuous reports, presentations and constantly conducted meetings with clients in order to achieve best results for them.

AMARA RAJA BATTERIES LTD

Senior Executive – Marketing (Nov'06 – May'11)

- Assisted managers in strategy planning. Was also part of the deliberation meetings and voiced an opinion as required.
- Responsible to execute the finalized marketing plans of the organization. The same had to be completed in a smooth and timely manner with justifiable results.
- Verbalized with various marketing heads regarding their marketing related expectations and communicated the same to the management and sort real time solutions for them.
- Executed various events, campaigns, road shows, scheme launches, handed PR work and press conferences for brand Amaron. Some events were budgeted at 2-3 crore.
- Managed the Amaron Go-carting challenge with was a high level event which sought to bring extensive brand visibility and growth to the brand. It involved PR activities, press conferences, lots of online & offline schemes & customer interactions.

IMPACT MARKETING SERVICE PVT. LTD., CHENNAI

Executive BTL Operations (Apr'06 - Oct'06)

- Associated with Sony brand while working with this organization.
- Handled various events, launched various schemes, trade shows, exhibitions etc. to improve brand visibility and help Sony achieve its marketing goals.
- Coordinated with various managerial heads at Sony as well as handled various managerial and executional teams to ensure timely completion of plans.

BRITT WORLD WIDE INDIA PVT. LIMITED, CHENNAI

Executive (May'01-Mar'06)

- A sister concern of Amway, profile consisted of executing various events and promotional activities as planned.
- Prepared event schedules, booked venues, cost planning, counter set ups etc. handled open meetings, business building seminars, summer conferences